¡÷Our server has custom Grape Juices weights. They are a very popular for being cheap and recovering a decent amount of SP.
#
¡÷Kokomo Beach (cmd_fild02) has 30 Mobsters instead of 1. They drop Sapphires which sell for quite a handful of Zeny to NPC's.
#
¡÷To create a guild you must have an Emperium and type /guild "Guild Name". To disband your guild. You have to expel every single Guild Member and type /breakguild "Guild Name".
#
¡÷The bank allows you to transfer money to another character on the same account. You can access it on most Kafra Employees.
#
¡÷Making a Merchant class helps to make more Zeny when selling drops with the Overcharge skill and saving money with the Discount skill when buying items from NPCs.
#
¡÷Do not share your account information with others. If you get scammed by them, GMs will charge a recovery fee to get them back.
#
¡÷Check forums everyday. You can meet new people, buy and sell items, give your opinions on debates and join events that are held on forums.
#
¡÷You can easily write into different chats without having to select the type of chat in your chat bar. To write a message to your party, simply place a % and a space before the message or hold ctrl when pressing enter. In order to send the message to your guild, simply add a $ before the text or hold the alt button when pressing enter.
#
¡÷To create a party use /organize "party name", to invite others into your party use /invite "character name", to kick someone out use the /expel "character name" and to leave a party simply enter /leave. You can also do those things by right-clicking on the related character name either normally or in the party window [alt+z].
#
¡÷If you do not wish to receive private messages from a single person, simply enter /ex "character name" to block all of his messages. If you want this person to be able to talk to you again, you'll have to enter /in "character name". You may also block/allow all incoming PMs by typing either /exall or /inall. To see you current block list, type /ex.
#
¡÷You can adjust the volume of sound and background music by clicking Options -> Sound Options. To turn on/off either BGM or sound effects, you can also just simply type in /bgm or /sound.
#
¡÷You can activate/deactivate several commands in Ragnarok Online. To see which ones you have activated and which not simply press [alt+y].
#
¡÷If you want to make some nice screen shots, simply press the Print Screen button on your keyboard. If you want to remove all the windows on your screen before making a nice screen shot, press [alt+f10] to remove the chat bar, [alt+end] to remove your HP/SP bar and [ctrl+tab] to remove the mini map. The basic information window can't be removed.
#
¡÷You can rotate your body while standing by typing either /bangbang (rotates clockwise) or /bingbing (rotates counterclockwise) and shake your head by typing /doridori.
#
¡÷Several dungeons will need you to have completed a quest before you may enter or to be able to proceed inside the dungeon. If you need any help with those quests, go check the forums!
#
¡÷If you're wondering why you can't talk to the NPCs in Umbala, you should know that you will have to learn their language first.
#
¡÷Ever heard about the new Pet Status system? Go try it our yourself, the NPCs selling everything you need are located east of the center of Prontera.
#
¡÷In order to change your job, you will have to go to the fountain in the center of Prontera. You can also receive a Cart, Peco Peco or Falcon in the building west of there, as well as some special skills for your class. Copies of some of those NPCs also can be found at the western side of Payon town.
#
¡÷Ingredients for Pharmacy and Forging can be bought near the northeastern house in the center of Prontera and south of the spawn location in Payon.
#
¡÷If you want to change your style, just visit the Stylist in the southwestern house in the center of Prontera.
#
¡÷You can have shops active, while not being logged on the related char! Just open a shop with the Merchant skill Vending and type in !autotrade. When you log onto the account again or when 48 hours have passed, the shop will automatically be disconnected.
#
¡÷If you want to send a message to the whole server, just use the !main command. This is an easy way of finding some friends to team up with. If the main chat is annoying you, simply turn it off by typing !main off.
#
¡÷You can search shops for the items you desire. Just type in !whosell  and you will get a list of all Merchants vending those items. To find out the IDs of specific items, go to http://cp.talonro.com.
#
¡÷Glast Heim Prison is a popular leveling area on TalonRO. Therefore it has been added to the Warp Girl, go check it out!
#
¡÷You can store your money in the Bank. This service is offered by any Kafra and is free of charge. If you don't want your money to get lost, it really is recommended to use this service!
#
¡÷Before you buy an expensive item, it is always useful to check other shops and the forums. This way you can make sure, that you will buy the desired item at an adequate price.
#
¡÷Make sure to read the Server Rules on the TalonRO website before starting to play. A proper interaction with both the GM team and other players is indispensable on this server.
#
¡÷Before opening a shop, make sure that you are following the official Vending Rules. Breaking these rules will result in a punishment by the GM team.
#
¡÷If you find any bugs in this game, make sure to report them immediately to the GM team. If you do so, you may receive a reward. If you exploit the bug, you will face punishment.
#
¡÷Never give out any money, items or information about your account to anyone. If you do so, you will have to take on full responsibility if something gets stolen.
#
¡÷Due to high demand, the number of monsters in nif_fild01 have been largely increased. If you don't know where to level, you might want to go check out this place.
#
¡÷The main chat should not be used for private talks between two players, but rather as a medium to share information with the entire server. Furthermore it should not be used to harass others on the main chat. GMs will give harsh punishments to people using any sort of vulgar language on the main chat.
#
¡÷TalonRO has some custom cards, i.e. original cards, which have been altered in order to make them more useful to the players. A full list of those cards can be found on the website.
#
¡÷In many cities you can find Soldiers which will mark the most important places on your map if you ask them to do so.
#
¡÷Got stuck in a quest? Check out all the the extremely useful quest guides in the forums!
#
¡÷Some of the events on TalonRO do not take place in the game itself, e.g. the Weekly Screenshot Event. More information about such events can be found on the forums.
#
¡÷To check the top ten ranking of the Taekwon class, simply type /taekwon.
#
¡÷To prevent yourself from accidently dropping items/equips while trading, use the !nodrop command.
#
¡÷Every 3 luk increases crit by 1.
#
¡÷Account bound dungeon entrance quests are those quests which allow you access those dungeons from any character from the same account after completing it once from any character.
#
¡÷The more people that hit the monster, more experience is given by the monster. This is useful in MvPing when more than 1 person is damaging the MvP.
#
¡÷Use /who to check the current online population
#
¡÷Meat weight has been changed to 2 from the normal weight of 15. They make a cheap and effective way to heal yourself while fighting monsters at lower levels.
#
¡÷Piece of cake weight has also been reduced to 1 from 10.
#
¡÷Tired of typing the whole name in the pm box? Just double click on the name of the person you want to pm in the regular chat log and his/her name will appear in the chat box.
#
¡÷By default, battlemode is enabled. Use the enter button to chat.
#
¡÷MVP equipment drops are not 3x. They are at the normal MVP drop rate.
#
¡÷Use the alt+I to open chats in different windows if you are getting multiple chats. Using this feature you can also send friend invitations if the other person is not on screen by right clicking the title bar of the chat window.
#
¡÷Use the reward guru npc to use the various facilities available via talonro coin such as rollback a class or change char name.
#
¡÷Use the tool shop infront of payon dungeon to buy silver arrows and the tool shop at sunken ship dungeon to buy fire arrows.
#
¡÷Make quivers to store great amount of arrows at less weight from the payon npc.
#
¡÷Some items are only available ingame through Talon Coins and vends, such as slotted elemental armors.
#
¡÷Remember to vote for us! Voting gets reward with Reward Points and helps to increase Experience Rates and Reward Points rates. You can vote from http://cp.talonro.com.
#
¡÷To see who are the top ten ranked Alchemists/Biochemists type /alchemist.
#
¡÷To see who are the top ten ranked Blacksmiths/Whitesmiths type /blacksmith.
#
¡÷To open the Tip of the Day type /tip.
#
¡÷To find out useful information about the entire Ragnarok Online game, you can use sites such as irowiki.org and ratemyserver.net.
#
¡÷Do not sell your cards to NPCs for a mere 10z. They are worth more than that.
#
¡÷How do you insert a card into an item? Put the item you want to insert a card in your inventory, then double click the card.
#
¡÷The location of party members in the same map are indicated on the mini-map at the upper right side. (Press CTRL+Tab if you don't see it) Party members are indicated with colored square which correspond to the color of their name in the Party Window (Alt+Z, Party). Guild members on the same map are indicated with a Pink Triangle.
#
¡÷When over upgrading gears past the safety limit (+4 for all armors, +4 to +7 depending on the level of weapon), there is a chance of breaking the item permanently. Any cards slotted in the gear will also be lost forever. It's best to over upgrade the gear first to your desired level and only slot the card later without risking the lost of cards.
#
¡÷Delay changing job and continue leveling as a Novice even after attaining job lvl 10. Leveling as a Novice with custom Novice gears is much easier and cheaper than class 2-1 with NPC gears.
#
¡÷, All players are considered medium size except for baby class. They are small size. Even Pecoriders are medium size.
#
¡÷How to PM (Private Message) someone: Type a character name at the left sided box of chat window, enter a message you want to send at the right sided box of the same window. TAB key moves cursor from one to another.
#
¡÷Ninja Magic Stones can only be purchased from the Ninja Guild, which is located at Amatsu Town. Entrance to the Guild is at (146,139). Walk through the wall (Secret Passage), behind the Scroll Painting, down the stairs and speak to Boonray (69,25).
#
¡÷Silver Bullets cost only 3z and can be bought from the Gunslinger Guild at Einbroch Town.
#
¡÷Eluniums are used for upgrading armors. 5 Rough Eluniums can be purified to make an Elunium for free by an NPC near the upgrade NPC located at various towns.
#
¡÷Lord Horn's Kaho gives +20STR +20DEX +20INT +20MDEF +6DEF and weighs only 10. A Kaho can be obtained via Talon Coins, a quest or it can be purchases from an existing player. The sprite of the Kaho can be customized to suit your taste for a little extra Talon Coins.
#
¡÷Oridecons are used for upgrading level 3 and 4 weapons. 5 Rough Oridecons can be purified to make an Oridecon for free by an NPC near the upgrade NPC located at various towns.
#
¡÷Sting card is a custom accessory card giving +4DEX. It is better than Zerom card which only gives +3DEX.
#
¡÷Alligator card is a custom weapon card giving +12CRIT. It is better than Skeleton Soldier card which only gives +9CRIT.
#
¡÷To become a Super Novice, you need a base level 45 Novice and job level 10.
#
¡÷Any refinement of weapon only increases ATK (physical attack) and not magical attack unless specifically stated. So a lvl 10 Firebolt from a +10Quad[Drops] Rod will do the same magical damage as a +0Quad [Drops] Rod.
#
¡÷What is a DDTT bow? What is DDSB mace? What is DTP? D= Doppelganger card. S= Incantation of Sammurai card. T= Turtle General card. B= Baphomet card. P= Phreeoni card.
#
¡÷Doppelganger card increases ASPD by 25%.
#
¡÷Racial damage cards such as Hydra cards do not increase magical damage. Do not make a +10 Quad Bloody[Hydra] Rod, hoping it will amplify your magical damage by 80% when attacking demi-human monsters/players.
#
¡÷At level 96, a Non-Transcendent is about the half-way mark towards level 99 (representing 49% of the total base experience required to reach level 99).
#
¡÷Keep those jellopies! Jellopy cannot be bought from any NPC. They are required to complete several quests namely Bio Lab Entrance Quest, Veins SIbling Quest (pre-requisite to enter Nameless Island), Mr Smile Quest and Helm of Orc Hero Quest. Jellopies can also be exchanged for Red Potions, made into arrows and is an ingredient to forge knives.
#
¡÷The player who delivers the final blow to the Emperium wins the castle for his/her guild.
#
¡÷Each armor refinement increases Hard DEF by 0.67.
#
¡÷Emperiums are also monsters. They are small in size. They are considered angel race and are of holy property.
#
¡÷Valkyrja's Shield[1] is a drop from Valkyrie Randgris (MVP) at 16%. Valkyrie Randgris can only be found at Odin Temple 03.
#
¡÷Most monster's melee attack are Neutral by default. Therefore, cards giving reduction from Neutral damage are much sought after such as Raydric Card (20% reduction in Neutral damage) and Deviling card (50% reduction in Neutral damage at the expense of receiving more damage from non-Neutral attacks).
#
¡÷DEX influences the success chance of Steal.
#
¡÷Asura (Guillotine fist) is a Neutral attack. It can be blocked by Safety Wall. Wearing a Ghostring Armor/Deviling Garment significantly reduces its damage.
#
¡÷There is a flee penalty of 20% during WOE.
#
¡÷CTRL+R to open Mercenary Window.
#
¡÷CTRL+U to open Quest Window.
#
¡÷There are three types of Mercenaries - Spearman, Fencer and Archer. They can be hired from Prontera Town, Izulde Town and Payon Archer Village respectively.
#
¡÷All Hunter traps last 4 times as long in WoE.
#
¡÷Every 10 Total LUK gives you 1 Perfect Dodge
#
¡÷Every 3 DEX, reduces your cast time by 2%.
#
¡÷The element of a frozen enemy is Water, which is weakest against Wind.
#
¡÷The element of a stone cursed enemy is Earth, which is weakest against Fire.
#
¡÷Pets gives some bonus stats when Loyal.
#
¡÷WOE 2.0 Guardians are considered as Boss monster.
#
¡÷What is SQI? It stands for Super Quest Items, a collection of 22 gears such as Mjolnir[3], Brysingamen [1] and Suiken[3]. All can be refined except for Mid Headgears and Accessories. They are the reward from completing the Super Quest.
#
¡÷How do I become a Transcendent? Level up any 2-1 Job class character to base 99, then talk to the Job Master NPC in the middle of Prontera to Rebirth for FREE.
#
¡÷If you receive a Gravity Error, make sure both your TalonRO and Sakray patches are up to date. If problems persist, make a post on the tRO forum under the Technical Support section.
#
¡÷Obeaune drops Necklace[1] at a 0.21% rate.
#
¡÷You do not lose any experience if you are killed on a No Death Penalty Maps - such as WOE castle maps, PVP maps and Town maps.
#
¡÷You can buy Rosary[0] from the Nun in Prontera Church (108, 124). For a mere 15,000z (before discount), you receive LUK + 2, MDEF + 5.
#
¡÷How to get a Slotted Elemental Armor such as Aebeccee's Raging Typhoon Armor [1]: Buy from other players or use the reward system for 10 Talon Coins.
#
¡÷You cannot Steal/Snatch/Gank a card from Monster.
#
¡÷The new location of Pheeroni (MVP) is moc_fild17.
#
¡÷Boss flagged monsters are immune to most Status effects such as Stun, Silenced, Frozen, Stone Curse, Poison, Blind, etc...
#
¡÷Panacea at 500z (before discount) can cure many ailments including Curse, Silenced, Blind, Chaos, Hallucination and Poison.
#
¡÷Know your elements. Example: Fire weapon/spells are strong against earth element monsters. http://ratemyserver.net/index.php?page=misc_table_attr
#
¡÷For World Map (Orbis of Midgard), Hold down CTRL and press "~" (the button, on the left side of "1") It indicates your current location and show an overview of other maps in the world of Ragnarok.
#
¡÷MVP Bonus is set at X50.
#
¡÷Chiqita's Jewelry Box (a custom drop at 0.3%) from Myst Case (which can be found in Toy Factory). Chiqita's Jewelry Box, when open, rewards you with a random one Mid Headgear (non-slotted).
#
¡÷Most mid-headgears can be slotted. They are a custom quest. Talk to Chiqita (NPC) in the bottom left building from the Middle of Prontera. More information can be found at www.talonro.com.
#
¡÷We have repeatable experience quest implemented on tRO. Basically, you are asked to gather some items, and present to an NPC, and it will reward you with some Base exp, Job exp and some additional items - normally HP healing item. More info, check http://forum.talonro.com/index.php/topic,22044.0.html.
#
¡÷To figure out your location. Type /where . It's good for finding an NPC during questing and letting people know where you are (i.e. which map and your current coordinates)
#
¡÷Acolyte class cannot memo warp on most field maps unless they are directly next to a town.
#
¡÷How to quit a guild? Press ALT + G, then look for your name, then right click and select leave.
#
¡÷How to open emoticon menu: ALT + L.
#
¡÷How to send a message to all your Friends on your friends list: Type /hi [message]
#
¡÷How to check the experience you are earning: Type !showexp
#
¡÷On TalonRO, you don't necessary need to level up a 99 Alchemist to become a Creator. You can switch classes when you rebirth. Example: a 99 Priest could become a Creator.
#
¡÷There are two Platinum Skill NPC in the game. She gives you the Platinum Skill of each class for FREE. One is located west of Payon (spawn point), the other inside the bottom left building from the middle of Prontera.
#
¡÷If you have a distant attacking class(hunter, archer, sniper) or a magic casting class, you can level easily on Geographers. Go to one map north of Einbroch and use a fire element attack against the Geo's. They can't chase you.
#
¡÷Marriage has benefits but its costly. Be sure you know your partner very well before tying the knot.
#
¡÷Baby classes can't transcend and only have max base stats of 80. But they have benefits from their parents such as auto sharing of exp as long as they are in range. No party needed!
#
¡÷Dex effects the crafting of weapons for Blacksmiths and potion making for Alchemists. It's better than luck by .01%
#
¡÷Bio lab is easy to open on even low level characters. But you must be at least lv 60 non-transcended to do the entrance quest. http://irowiki.org/wiki/Biolabs_Entrance_Quest
#
¡÷Use the command /q2 to use the mouse wheel not for zooming in and out but now to rapid heal using skill, items, etc.
#
¡÷/ns stands for no shift. When entered you don't have to hold the shift key to heal players or monsters (which damages undead).
#
¡÷There are some monsters that will use a spell to cause your screen to appear wavy and blurry. You can type /effect to halt all animations of this kind and any others. Note: in doing so, you can't see your own animations as well nor can you see warp portals to other maps (only a shadow will be there).
#
¡÷ASPD (attack speed) maxes out at 190 on our server. This means you'll do five attacks a second. Various weapons affect your ASPD (axes are slowest and bare hands is fastest) and many cards affect this as well. The main stats that affects this are AGI and DEX by approximately 1/5.
#
¡÷DEX affects your hit rate. Hit is affected by DEX 1 to 1 and by your base level. DEX also reduces your cast time. Instant Casting requires a DEX stat of 150 or more. Also Hit= total DEX + base level.
#
¡÷Make sure you use multiple skills both in PvP and PvM. Knowing which skill to use at the right time can change who dies in battle.
#
¡÷Make sure you pick up all your loot. Loot makes Zeny. People make Zeny make tRO go 'round.
#
¡÷Sometimes in battle, retreating isn't the same as losing. If things look bad... RUN. Retreating and regrouping can keep you alive and prevent EXP loss.
#
¡÷Don't rush in to a fight with an MvP Class Monster. Charging in without thinking is cruisin' for a bruisin'. Make sure you have all the bases covered in an MvP fight.
#
¡÷Nothing ventured, nothing gained. If you like the idea, at least give it a try. You won't get very far if you're training in the same place all the time. You may find an even better training spot than the norms!
#
¡÷Save your money, but don't be stingy! If you have an item, make use of it! After all, something sitting in ones stash doesn't help you, or the someone who may want it!
#
¡÷When changing your equipment, consider the trade offs when you unequip your current equipment for something new. Is the trade off worth it? Is it pretty much the same? One way to get around this by carrying a good amount of equipment to handle various situations. Be wary of weight limits though.
#
¡÷Don't pour all your stat points into one stat. You could have muscles to match Satan Morroc, but if you lack the dexterity to hit something, they're worthless! Remember also that DEX affects your cast time, making it one of the more important stats in the game. Also keep in mind that you could also attack at the speed of light, but you'll need some brute force behind your blows if you're to do some real damage. Each class has different uses for each stat, so make sure you keep that in mind as well.
#
¡÷No mercy! Always attack with all you can dish out. Don't expect a monster in game to hold anything back, so you've got no reason to pull any punches!
#
¡÷After promoting from a Novice, you will suffer a death penalty upon death. Don't bite more than you can chew.
#
¡÷Pets and Homuculi are different, anyone may own a pet which gives player stats but only alchemists may own homuculi which can help with battle.
#
¡÷Alchemists acquire Homuculii through skills, players must earn pets by catching monsters for eggs and hatching them.
#
¡÷Philosopher's stone are for evolving Homuculii, they may only be used when the Homuculus is loyal.
#
¡÷Pets and Homuculii must be fed or they run away, type of feed required may be found in skill info for Homuculous and at the pet NPCs for pets.
#
¡÷Homuculii and pet loyalty are based on intimacy points gained through feeding and amount of time spent accompanying you while battling.
#
¡÷Pets and Homuculii must not be over fed or intimacy points will be deducted whereas higher points will be rewarded when they are fed while hungry
#
¡÷Homuculus type and stats are distributed randomly though player stats may influence type summoned, Homuculus stats are influenced by type.
#